### **JASON E. MILLER**

jaericm@yahoo.com

1217 W. Rosemont Avenue, #1, Chicago, IL 60660 773.551.9563

With twenty-five years in technology, I have in-depth experience in evaluating, documenting, implementing and configuring software applications in the US and internationally. As a developer, I specialize in node/javascript-based, full-stack, applications that often reference other tools, libraries, and frameworks, such as jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, or Express, and utilize storage and deployment applications such as GitHub and Heroku.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Senior Analyst, Northwestern University (June 2017 to present)

- Gathered and documented requirements for cross-team projects and implementations.
- Facilitated feedback and input sessions on software/tool acquisitions across a broad stakeholder audience.
- Guided project portfolio management for the Enabling Technologies team.
- Provided project management using both waterfall and agile/SCRUM approaches (PMP & SCRUM certified).
- Managed University implementations of OnBase & PerfectForms (workflow tools) as product owner.
- Managed University implementations of Tosca & Katalon Studios (functional testing tools) as product owner, which includes writing code (Groovy) and extensive trouble-shooting during test creation.
- Championed DevOps implementations and education across the IT organization.
- Co-chaired a project manager practitioner forum.

# Content Services Manager, Tribridge (March 2012 to April 2017)

- Supervised scope, schedule, and resources for LMS implementation and custom content projects.
- Analyzed and responded to RFPs detailing content-specific solutions for Tribridge clients.
- Provided thought leadership to Tribridge clients on content management, development, and trends.
- Augmented clients' industry knowledge through blogs, webinars, and conference speaking engagements.
- Created scope documentation for all content projects.
- Created and documented custom content development processes.
- Managed both instructional design and production teams, including off-shore content production teams.
- Conducted basic and advanced training sessions on Claro functionality.
- Acted as an implementation consultant for Cornerstone implementations (certified March 2012 on CSOD LMS implementations).

### Self-Employed Contractor, JMiller Consulting LLC (February 2011 to March 2012)

- Conducted needs analysis for the unique learning and training needs of an organization.
- Assisted organizations in developing online learning strategies, including instructional design.
- Managed the implementation, configuration, and technical aspects of online learning and content management systems.
- Architected process for transforming legacy content and formats into more advanced versions.
- Creating process and tools for developing content, including schema/DTD development for structured environments.

#### **Customers include:**

- Thunderhead (communications / enterprise management) Configured LMS (Moodle) to maximize eLearning requirements; developed a macro-level instructional design and developed SCORM-based modules for new-hire training.
- Leading Real Estate Companies of the World Created XML-based authoring tool for rapid development of SCORM-based eLearning; analyzed and wrote documentation/training for LMS best practice and content development cycles.
- Jericho Resources Created three Access databases and the training materials (both print and eLearning modules) to go with them.
- Kaplan Distance Learning (UK) Performed a needs assessment for an online tool that helped students organize
  their long-term self-study programs and was re-engaged for a follow-up project for which I wrote the technical
  requirements for the tool.

### Director of Enterprise Content Technology, Kaplan Higher Education (May 2010 to February 2011)

- Represented KHE within the larger Kaplan enterprise in strategies concerning learning management system enhancements, as well as content storage, transformation, and development roadmaps.
- Acted as a liaison between the individual schools (business units) and the CMS/LMS technology teams.
- Designed a production workflow and implemented agile-oriented workflow software (Target Process) to monitor project progress, resources, and time allocation.
- Oversaw the conversion of 1,000 online courses from various legacy formats into one centralized format, creating the workflow, schedules, resource plan, and instructional design.
- Wrote technical and training documentation for the conversion process
- Managed an off-shore team in India of 50 content developers, media developers, and QA specialists.

# Learning Technologies Manager, Kaplan Publishing, United Kingdom (March 2007 to April 2010)

- Implemented, configured, staffed, and maintained the content management system (CMS) and learning management system (LMS) for use across all Kaplan Publishing UK and Kaplan Financial UK.
- Hired, trained, and managed the team responsible for content creation, instructional design, XML mark-up (using XML-based authoring tools), and LMS deployment and day-to-day usage.
- Developed a detailed succession plan for the LMS department (as part of my return to the US office)
- Integrated an off-shore team in India (18+ members) into the UK production process, maximizing their scalability/availability of advanced skills (such as media post-production and instructional design).
- Created and enforced process and standards for content production and LMS deployments.
- Established re-usable content models, with an emphasis on outputting the same underlying content into print, online (SCORM 2004 objects), mobile, CD, etc.
- Specialized in architecting process for transforming legacy formats into structured formats.
- Developed and implemented the project plan for an XML output of tests directly to an iTunes mobile application (reuse model from existing source content).
- Balanced schedule, resource, and scope for core business projects, as well as adapting and expanding the process to other parts of the Kaplan UK business outside of Kaplan Publishing.
- Analyzed content technology enhancement requests and translated them into a well-defined scope documents.
- Forecasted expenses and created detailed budgets of over \$800,000 USD.
- Supervised the building of a sound-proof audio-visual studio for filming and A/V production.

# Director of eLearning Services, Kaplan Professional (August 2005 to February 2007)

- Guided the vision and process planning for the suite of products and tools used to author content and provide output to the online platform, CD-ROM, SCO, and print.
- Analyzed requirements for new features/functionality, in addition to designing process that would incorporate the new features into updated products or better utilize the new functionality for a more efficient production workflow.
- Monitored the eLearning Services suite of tools to ensure that it met the needs of the business units, both as an interdependent suite and as individual components.
- Communicated the status, such as new releases, sunset plans, interdependencies, and updates/patches.
- Coordinated the releases of platforms, tools, and utilities to coordinate functionality and underlying data changes.
- Supervised the eLearning Services team and delegated project management assignments.
- Wrote end-user documentation and provided end-user training for each release of tools.

# Senior Production Analyst & Project Manager, Kaplan Professional (April 2001 to July 2005)

- Acted as technical lead on all format-conversion projects, including SGML to XML (500 courses), Access tables to XML (30,000 questions), and HTML to XML.
- Performed ongoing gap analysis of tools and processes, resulting in new documented processes and sets of interim tools.
- Developed Visual Basic tools to create and manipulate valid XML files for new platform.
- Gathered requirements and oversaw the process for new platform releases.
- Trained and developed QA resources on the intricacies of the authoring platform and provided guidance for writing test scripts.

## Securities Editor & Online Product Manager, Kaplan Professional (March 1997 to March 2001)

- Managed the online securities pre-licensing product line.
- Converted print-based material into multimedia formats such as CD-ROM and online (including all HTML programming for various online deployments).
- Created and maintained departmental databases for more than 12,000 securities-related exam questions re-used among 60 products.

# Compliance & Call Center, Kaplan Professional (February 1996 to February 1997)

• Managed submissions of course approvals for each state. Responsible for updating and automating many of the procedures and increasing turn-around and output efficiencies.

#### Teacher, Peace Corps, Ethiopia (June 1995 to January 1996)

• Taught English as a second language and sex education to over 400 students in two villages.

#### Language Arts Teacher, St. Joachim Grade School (August 1992 to July 1994)

Designed and taught writing and reading curriculum for junior high language arts program.

### English Teacher, Percy Julian High School (Dec 1991 to June 1992)

• Designed and taught English literature and writing course, 11th grade level.

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

- Northwestern Full-Stack Developer Bootcamp, 2020
- SCRUM Alliance, SCRUM Master certified, 2019
- Project Management Institute, Project Management Professional (PMP) certified, 2004
- University of Chicago, CE course in Manuscript Editing, 1998
- National Lewis University, 15 hours toward Masters in Writing Pedagogy, 1993
- Olivet University, B.A., Magna Cum Laude in English Education, Minor in Psychology, 1991

#### **LMS IMPLEMENTED**

- Cornerstone
- Moodle
- e2train's Kallidus
- Ziiva's Prosperity
- Pearson's eCollege
- Kaplan Learning Platform (an XML-based proprietary platform)

### **SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS (INDUSTRY CONFERENCES)**

- Learning Technologies Conference, London, 2008
- Society of Applied Learning Technologies (SALT) Conference, Washington DC, 2011
- Learning Dev Camp Conference, Salt Lake City, UT, 2014
- Learning Dev Camp Conference, Salt Lake City, UT, 2016

### **WEBINAR LINKS**

- Avoid the Flash Dance: Planning for the end of Flash-Based Content
- Yours, Mine and Ours: Achieving the Right Mix of Custom and Off-the-Shelf Learning Content
- Lost in Translation

#### **OTHER NOTABLE SKILLS**

Visio, Visual Basic, advanced Microsoft Access, various XML editors and validation tools, Claro, Articulate Presenter, Captivate, Camtasia, Adobe Presenter, PerfectForms (workflow creation tool), TargetProcess (Agile development workflow tool). Outstanding organizational, leadership, and communication skills.